Register of the Eric Voegelin papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Speeches and Writings, 1921-1987
  - Speech relating to speculative histories and related interview, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia, 1974 October (Box-folder 80: 5)
    Clippings
  - Speech, American Academy of Religion, Florida State University, Tallahassee, Florida, 1974 October 26 (Box-folder 80: 6)
    Correspondence with Walter L. Moore
  - "The Quest of Truth,", circa 1975 (Box-folder 80: 7)
  - From Enlightenment to Revolution, 1975
    - Typescript (Box-folder 80: 8-10)
    - Reviews
      - General (Box-folder 80: 11)
      - Havard, William C., "Voegelin's Diagnosis of the Western Crisis" (Box-folder 81: 1)
      - Sandoz, Ellis, "From Enlightenment to Revolution" (Box-folder 81: 2)
      - Sebba, Gregor, "Eric Voegelin: From Enlightenment to Universal Humanity." (Box-folder 81: 3)
        Typescript and printed copy. Includes correspondence
  - Series of speeches, Visiting Scholars Program, University Center in Virginia, Richmond, Virginia, 1975 March 11-13 (Box-folder 81: 4)
    Correspondence with W. Donald Rhinesmith and Jeannette R. Boughman
  - "The Beginning and the Beyond,", 1975 May 18 (Box-folder 81: 5)
    Aquinas lecture, Marquette University, Milwaukee, Wisconsin. Research material, typescript, and correspondence with Francis C. Wade
  - "Theophany in Plato's Dialogues,", 1975 September 3 (Box-folder 81: 6)
    Conference paper, American Political Science Association, Seventy-first Annual Meeting, San Francisco, California. Outline and correspondence with Harvey C. Mansfield, Jr.
  - Speech relating to The Ecumenic Age, University of Dallas, Irving, Texas, 1975 November (Box-folder 81: 7)
    Correspondence with Daniel J. Davis
  - "Civilizational Encounters and the Genesis of Humanity,", 1976 April 2 (Box-folder 82: 1)
    Speech, International Society for the Comparative Study of Civilizations, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. Announcement
  - "Reality in the Topical Cover-Ups,", 1976 May 27 (Box-folder 82: 2)
    Speech, Santa Barbara, California. Outline
  - "The Beginning and the Beyond,", 1976 October 13 (Box-folder 82: 3)
    Speech, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia. Correspondence with Dante Germino and clipping
  - "Wisdom and the Magic of the Extreme,", 1977 August 23
    Conference paper, Eranos Tagung, Ascona, Switzerland
    - Notes and outline (Box-folder 82: 4)
    - Typescript (Box-folder 82: 5)
    - Galley proofs (Box-folder 82: 6)
    - Correspondence with Rudolf Ritsema, Adolf Portmann, Ellis Sandoz, Southern Review (Box-folder 82: 7)
  - Series of three speeches, entitled "The Truth of Reason," "The Truth of Vision," and "The Beginning and the Beyond," Syracuse University, Syracuse, New York, 1977 October 31 - November 2 (Box-folder 82: 8)
    Outlines and clipping
  - "Athens and Jerusalem--Under the Pressure Empire,", 1978 March 29 (Box-folder 82: 9)
    Speech, University of Houston, Texas. Outline and correspondence with Stephen Langfur
  - "The Drama of Humanity,", 1967 April 17-20 (Box-folder 82: 10)
    Conference paper, Conference for the Study of Political Thought, Loyola University, Chicago, Illinois. Correspondence with James L. Wiser and Roger D. Masters
  - "The Symbolism of the Beyond,", 1978 April 11 (Box-folder 82: 11)
    Speech, St. Michael's College, University of Toronto, Ontario. Correspondence with Kenneth Keulman and Thomas Langan
  - "The Drama of Humanity,", 1978 April 13 (Box-folder 82: 12)
    Speech, Earlham College, Richmond, Indiana. Correspondence with Paul Caringella
  - "The Structure of Modernity,", 1978 April 28
    Public lecture, Conference on Gnosticism and Modernity, Vanderbilt University, Nashville, Tennessee
    - Outline (Box-folder 83: 1)
    - Proceedings (Box-folder 83: 2-3)
    - Correspondence with Richard J. Bishirjian, William C. Havard, Jürgen Gebhardt (Box-folder 83: 4)
  - "The Function of Classical Philosophy in our Time,", 1978 October 19 (Box-folder 83: 5)
    Speech, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, Michigan. Outline and correspondence with Charles Trinkaus and John R. O'Connor
  - Conference paper, Hermeneutics & Structuralism: Merging Horizons, An International Conference, The Literary Society of York, York University, Toronto, Ontario, 1978 November 22-24 (Box-folder 83: 6)
    Correspondence with Thomas Langan, Nicholas Graham, Brayton Polka
  - Speech relating to human nature, The Colorado College, Colorado Springs, Colorado, 1978 November 28 (Box-folder 84: 1)
    Correspondence with Timothy Fuller
  - "Structures in Consciousness,", 1979 April 3 (Box-folder 84: 2)
    Suarez lecture, Spring Hill College, Mobile, Alabama. Outline and clipping
  - "Structures in Consciousness,", 1979 April 4 (Box-folder 84: 3)
    Speech, Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, Louisiana. Correspondence with Ellis Sandoz and Beverly Jarrett (Louisiana State University Press). For outline, see "Structures in Consciousness," 3 April 1979
  - "Wisdom and the Magic of the Extreme,", 1979 July 12-14 (Box-folder 84: 4)
    Speech, Summer Institute, Extending Theoretical Foundations: Applications of Theories to Subfields of Political Science, Vanderbilt University, Nashville, Tennessee. Correspondence with William C. Havard and George J. Graham, Jr.
  - "Wisdom and the Magic of the Extreme,", 1979 October 6, 8 (Box-folder 84: 5)
    Speech, Symposia at Stony Brook and Binghamton, New York. Correspondence with Ray L. Hart
  - "Wisdom and the Magic of the Extreme: The Platonic Analysis and Its Continuity,", 1979 October 10 (Box-folder 84: 6)
    Faber lecture, Princeton University, Princeton, New Jersey. Outline and correspondence with Steven Shankman
  - "The Consciousness of History: A Study of Plato's Nomoi,", 1979 October 24 (Box-folder 84: 7)
    Speech, The University of Utah, Salt Lake City, Utah. Correspondence with Richard S. Tompson
  - Speech, University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, Minnesota, 1979 November 15 (Box-folder 84: 8)
    Correspondence with Robert T. Holt
  - Outlines, 1979-1983 (Box-folder 84: 9)
  - Conversations with Eric Voegelin, 1980
    Transcript of four lectures and discussions held at the Thomas More Institute for Adult Education in Montreal
    - "In Search of the Ground,", 1965 February 28 (Box-folder 84: 10)
      Speech. Outline and typescript
    - "Theology Confronting World Religions?", 1967 October 16 (Box-folder 84: 11)
    - "Questions Up,", 1970 November 9 (Box-folder 84: 12)
      Interview. Typescript
    - "Myth as Environment,", 1976 March 12 (Box-folder 84: 13)
      Seminar. Typescript
    - Correspondence with Eric O'Connor, 1965-1981 (Box-folder 84: 14)
  - "Magic and Politics,", 1980 February 19 (Box-folder 84: 15)
    Speech, University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, Minnesota. Outline and correspondence with Robert T. Holt and Benjamin E. Lippincott
  - "Existential Consciousness,", 1980 April 14 (Box-folder 84: 16)
    Speech, University of Notre Dame, South Bend, Indiana. Outline and correspondence with Fred R. Dallmayr and Gerhart Niemeyer
  - "The Magic of the Extreme,", 1980 April 22-23 (Box-folder 84: 17)
    Series of two speeches, The Edward Douglass White Lectures on Citizenship, Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, Louisiana. Outline, clipping, and correspondence with Cecil V. Crabb, Jr.
  - Interview, Norddeutscher Rundfunk, Hamburg, circa 1980 April 28 (Box-folder 84: 18)
    Correspondence with Michael Hereth (interviewer), Walter Helfer, Michael Naumann
  - "Der meditative Ursprung philosophischen Ordnungswissens,", 1980 September 23 (Box-folder 84: 19)
    Paper, Politische Philosophie Heute, Wissenschaftliches Symposium mit Eric Voegelin, Tutzing, West Germany. Printed copy and correspondence with Jürgen Gebhardt and Eva Czwientzek
  - "Politics as Magic,", 1980 October 16
    Conference paper, Colloque Culture et Politique, European University Institute, Florence, Italy
    - Notes and typescript (Box-folder 84: 20)
    - Proceedings (Box-folder 84: 21)
    - Correspondence with Athanasios Moulakis, Maurice Cranston, Max Kohnstamm, Robert L. Richards (United States. International Communication Agency) (Box-folder 84: 22)
  - "Magic Dreams in Politics,", 1980 November 14-15 (Box-folder 84: 23)
    Series of four talks leading the Fall Retreat of the Stanford Memorial Church, Redwood City, California. Outline and correspondence with Robert Hamerton-Kelly
  - Epilogue to Eric Voegelin's Thought: A Symposium, 1981
    - Typescript (Box-folder 85: 1)
    - Correspondence with Ellis Sandoz (Box-folder 85: 2)
  - "Menschheit und Geschichte," Zeitschrift für Politik, 1981 (Box-folder 85: 3)
  - "Die Symbolisierung der Ordnung," Politische Studien, January/February 1981 (Box-folder 85: 4)
  - "Das öffentliche Unbewusstsein,", 1981 May 21 (Box-folder 85: 5)
    Speech, Ludwig-Maximilians-Universität München, Munich, West Germany. Outline and correspondence with Heinz Laufer, Peter J. Opitz, Nikolaus Lobkowicz, Hans Maier, Helmut Kuhn, Jürgen Gebhardt, Ursula Sens, Eva Czwientzek, Manfred Henningsen, Johannes von Elmenau, Wolfgang Pannenberg
  - "Die Ordnung der Geschichte enthält sich in der Geschichte der Ordnung," Politische Studien, 1981 May/June (Box-folder 85: 6)
  - "Wisdom and the Magic of the Extreme,", 1982 March 12 (Box-folder 85: 7)
    Conference paper, The Metaphysical Society of America, Thirty-third Annual Meeting, The Catholic University of America, Washington, D.C. Outline and correspondence with Thomas Langan, Edmund D. Pellegrino, Jude P. Dougherty
  - "Vision and Parousia,", 1982 March 16 (Box-folder 85: 8)
    Speech, Boston University, Boston, Massachusetts. Outline and correspondence with Alan M. Olson, Leroy S. Rouner
  - "Reflections on Wisdom and the Magic of the Extreme,", 1982 March 20 (Box-folder 85: 9)
    Conference paper, Mysticism in Literature, Conference on Christianity and Literature, New England Region Meeting, Boston University, Boston, Massachusetts. Announcement. For correspondence with Alan M. Olson, see "Vision and Parousia," 16 March 1982
  - "The Beyond and Its Parousia,", 1982 October 15 (Box-folder 85: 10)
    Conference paper, The Meaning of History, University of Santa Clara, California. Outline, typewritten transcript from taped presentation, and correspondence with James W. Felt
  - Opening and closing remarks, The Beginning and the Beyond: A Symposium on the Work of Eric Voegelin, Putnam Center, Boston College, Chestnut Hill, Massachusetts, 1983 March 25-26 (Box-folder 85: 11)
    Outline and correspondence with Joseph Flanagan
  - Conversations, The Lonergan Symposium, University of Santa Clara, California, 1984 March 16 (Box-folder 85: 12)
    Correspondence with William J. Rewak
  - Order and History, Vol.V: In Search of Order, 1987 (Box-folder 85: 13)
- Course Material, 1928-1974
  Correspondence, course catalogs, examination questions, memoranda, notes, reading lists, roll lists, and syllabi, arranged alphabetically by university
  - General
    - Examination questions (Box-folder 86: 1)
    - Reading lists (Box-folder 86: 2)
    - Research material and notes
      - 1930s (Box-folder 86: 3)
      - 1940s-1950s (Box-folder 86: 4)
      - 1960s (Box-folder 86: 5)
      - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 86: 6)
    - Syllabi
      - International relations (Box-folder 86: 7)
      - Political science, outline, circa 1938-1940 (Box-folder 86: 8)
  - Geschwister-Scholl-Institut für Politische Wissenschaft (Universität München)
    - "Ostasiatische Politik," lecture transcript, undated (Box-folder 86: 9)
    - "Rechtsphilosophie," syllabus and reading list, undated (Box-folder 86: 10)
    - "Einführung in die Politik," notes and lecture transcript, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 86: 11)
    - "Hitler und die Deutsche," lecture course, 1964
      - Reading list (Box-folder 86: 12)
      - Reading notes (Box-folder 86: 13)
      - Research material
        - General (Box-folder 86: 14)
        - General (Box-folder 87: 1)
        - Churches
          - Catholic (Box-folder 87: 2)
          - Protestant (Box-folder 87: 3)
        - Hitler (Box-folder 87: 4)
        - Liberalism (Box-folder 87: 5)
        - Marxism, nationalsocialism, fascism, capitalism (Box-folder 87: 6)
        - Rechtsstaat (Box-folder 87: 7)
        - Socialism, syndicalism, communism (Box-folder 87: 8)
      - Typescript (Box-folder 87: 9-17)
    - "Geschichtsphilosophie,", 1968 (Box-folder 88: 1)
      Contians a syllabus, notes, research material, and a student paper.
    - "Theorie der Politik," notes and reading list, 1968 (Box-folder 88: 2)
    - Untitled lecture, 1968 May 15 (Box-folder 88: 3)
      Transcript of exchange between Eric Voegelin and students who interrupted his lecture, correspondence, notes, clippings, and background material.
    - "Moderne politische Theorie,", 1968-1969 (Box-folder 88: 4)
      Syllabus, reading list, notes.
  - Harvard University
    - Reading lists and correspondence with George W. Adams and Rupert Emerson, 1949 (Box-folder 88: 5)
    - Roll lists, reading lists, examination questions, and correspondence with Carl J. Friedrich, Arthur Maass, and Wilfred Cantwell Smith, 1964 (Box-folder 88: 6)
  - Louisiana State University
    - "Russia and Eastern Europe,", 1951 (Box-folder 88: 7)
      Contains correspondence with Donald MacLean.
    - "China and Japan," notes and examination questions, 1952 (Box-folder 88: 8)
    - "Jurisprudence,", 1954 (Box-folder 88: 9)
      Notes, research material, outline, examination questions, and roll lists.
    - "The Nature of the Law,", 1957 (Box-folder 88: 10)
      Notes and transcript of series of lectures. See also Incremental Speeches and Writings (Box 118, Folders 3-5).
  - Stanford University
    - Correspondence with the Political Science Department, 1969-1974 (Box-folder 88: 11)
    - "Ancient Oriental Empires and Israel,", 1970 (Box-folder 89: 1)
      Includes reading lists and student papers.
    - "Theory of Revolution,", 1970 (Box-folder 89: 2)
      Includes reading lists, roll lists, abstracts, syllabi, memoranda, and correspondence.
    - "Greek Religion from Homer to Alexander,", 1972 (Box-folder 89: 3)
      Includes reading lists, roll lists, notes, examination questions, memoranda, and correspondence.
    - "Values, Technology and Science,", 1972
      - Correspondence with the Humanities Department (William A. Clebsch) (Box-folder 89: 4)
      - Proposals, including minutes (Box-folder 89: 5-6)
  - Universität zu Wien, Vienna, Austria, course catalogs, 1928-1938 (Box-folder 89: 7)
  - University of Alabama, 1941 (Box-folder 90: 1)
    Correspondence, clippings, and copies of the essay written by the three students of Eric Voegelin who won the regional prize in the contest for the William and Mary Prizes on American Foreign Policy.
  - University of Dallas, 1972 (Box-folder 90: 2)
    Notes, roll lists, reading lists, examination questions, memoranda, and correspondence.
  - University of Michigan, 1967 (Box-folder 90: 3)
    Correspondence with Stephen J. Tonsor, William B. Willcox, Otto G. Graf, and Frank Grace.
  - University of Notre Dame
    - Correspondence, 1959-1976 (Box-folder 90: 4)
      Includes material with Paul E. Beichner, George Brinkley, Ferdinand L. Brown, John Gueguen, Theodore M. Hesburgh, John J. Kennedy, Stephen D. Kertesz, Ernan McMullin, Stanley Parry, C. A. Soleta, Thomas E. Stewart, and John E. Walsh.
    - Circulars and memoranda, 1960-1974 (Box-folder 90: 5)
    - Miscellany, 1961-1974 (Box-folder 90: 6-10)
      Contains synopsis, examination questions, roll lists, reading lists, memoranda, and notes.
  - University of Southern California
    - "Theory of the Capitalist Economy," with Frank H. Knight and Ludwig von Mises, 1953 June-July (Box-folder 90: 11)
      Contains correspondence with Lawrence C. Lockley.
    - Correspondence with Alberto Guerreiro-Ramos regarding the canceled fall seminar of 1974 (Box-folder 90: 12)
  - University of Texas at Austin, "Theory of Revolution,", 1975 (Box-folder 90: 13)
    Contains syllabi, reading lists, and examination questions.
- Office File, Geschwister-Scholl-Institut für Politische Wissenschaft (Universität München), 1956-1983
  Correspondence, memoranda, reports, and studies from the Geschwister-Scholl-Institut für Politische Wissenschaft (Universität München), arranged alphabetically by physical form
  - Correspondence with Bayerischer Staatsminister für Unterricht und Kultus (Johannes von Elmenau), Universität München, Alois Dempf, Helmut Kuhn, Hans Maier, Hedda Herwig
    See also CORRESPONDENCE, Friedemann Büttner and Nikolaus Lobkowicz
    - 1956-1958 (Box-folder 91: 1)
    - 1959-1968 (Box-folder 91: 2)
    - Regarding the controversy between the Institute and the Hochschule für Politische Wissenschaften, 1965 (Box-folder 91: 3)
    - Regarding Eric Voegelin's successor, 1968-1972 (Box-folder 91: 4)
    - Regarding guest professorships, 1983 (Box-folder 91: 5)
  - Guidelines, 1962 (Box-folder 91: 6)
  - Handbook, 1962 (Box-folder 91: 7)
  - Library cataloging system guide, 1961 (Box-folder 91: 8)
  - Memoranda, 1959 and 1965 (Box-folder 91: 9)
  - Minutes, 1968 (Box-folder 91: 10)
  - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 91: 11)
  - Research project, undated (Box-folder 91: 12)
  - Seminar outline (Heinz Laufer), 1962-1963 (Box-folder 91: 13)
- Subject File, 1881-1983
  Dissertations, essays, newsletters, reports, school papers, studies, clippings, and other printed matter, arranged alphabetically by subject
  - Akademie für Politik und Zeitgeschehen der Hanns-Seidel- Stiftung. See CORRESPONDENCE, Hermann Warth
  - Akademie für Politische Bildung, Tutzing (Box-folder 91: 14)
  - Alexander the Great (Box-folder 91: 15)
  - Alfred Schütz Memorial Fund (Box-folder 91: 16)
    Appeal list and correspondence
  - Apocalypse (Box-folder 92: 1)
  - Archeology (Box-folder 92: 2)
  - Aristotle (Box-folder 92: 3)
  - Arnold, Gottfried (Box-folder 92: 4)
  - Art, Contemporary (Box-folder 92: 5)
  - Austria (Box-folder 92: 6)
    See also CORRESPONDENCE, Austrian Institute (for a detailed outline of a speech by Ernst Hoor), Clara Hausel, Erich Hula, Robert G. Neumann
  - Austrians - United States (Box-folder 92: 7)
    List. See also CORRESPONDENCE, American Defense.
  - Bakunin, Mikhail (Box-folder 92: 8)
  - Bergson, Henri (Box-folder 92: 9)
  - Bodin, Jean (Box-folder 92: 10)
  - Bonaparte, Louis Napoléon (Box-folder 92: 11)
    Speeches by Jakob Burckhardt. Typescript
  - Buckley, William F., Jr. See CORRESPONDENCE, Vazquez, Edward H.
  - Bundesgesetzblatt für den Bundesstaat Osterreich, 1920-1936 (Box-folder 92: 12)
  - Campanella, Tommaso (Box-folder 92: 13)
  - Camus, Albert (Box-folder 92: 14)
  - Center for Coordination of Ancient and Modern Studies. Includes notes of Eric Voegelin regarding the First Planning Conference, January 30-31, 1970 (Box-folder 92: 15)
  - Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions (Box-folder 92: 16)
  - China (Box-folder 92: 17)
  - Christian Science (Box-folder 92: 18)
    Includes notes by Eric Voegelin
  - Christians Concerned for Israel (Box-folder 92: 19)
  - Civilizations, History of (Box-folder 92: 20)
  - Columbia University (Box-folder 92: 21)
  - Committee for the Study of Mankind (Box-folder 92: 22)
  - Coomaraswamy, Ananda K. (Box-folder 92: 23)
  - Descartes, René (Box-folder 93: 1)
  - Deutsche Gesellschaft für Soziologie (Box-folder 93: 2)
  - Deutsche Vereinigung für Politische Wissenschaft (Box-folder 93: 3)
  - Drama (Box-folder 93: 4)
  - Eclecticism (Box-folder 93: 5)
  - Economics (Box-folder 93: 6)
  - Engel-Janosi, Friedrich (Box-folder 93: 7)
  - Ervin, Sam J., Jr. (Box-folder 93: 8)
  - Europe - Geography (Box-folder 93: 9)
  - Europeans - United States (Box-folder 93: 10)
  - Exchange (Box-folder 93: 11)
  - Farabi (Box-folder 94: 1)
  - Fatum et Fortuna (Box-folder 94: 2)
  - Foundations of Political Theory Group Panels (Box-folder 94: 3)
  - Franklin, H. Bruce (Box-folder 94: 4)
  - Free Austrian Movement in Great Britain. See Austria
  - Freedom & Union (Box-folder 94: 5)
  - Fritz Thyssen Stiftung. Includes financial records regarding the Geschwister-Scholl-Institut für Politische Wissenschaft (Universität München) (Box-folder 94: 6)
  - Fulbright Commission (Box-folder 94: 7)
  - Genetics (Box-folder 94: 8)
  - Georgetown University, Center for Strategic Studies (Box-folder 94: 9)
  - Germany (East). See CORRESPONDENCE, Walter Friedrich
  - Germany (West)
    - Economic conditions-. See CORRESPONDENCE, Klara and Fritz Härdtl, Hede and Karl Koch, Peter Koch, Ulrich Onken, Fritz Rühl, Hedwig Rühl, 1945-
    - Education (Box-folder 94: 10)
    - Politics
      - 1933-1945 (Box-folder 94: 11)
      - 1955-1980 (Box-folder 94: 12)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 94: 13)
  - Geschichte des politischen Denkens (Society for the Advancement of Political Science and History) (Box-folder 94: 14)
  - Geschwister-Scholl-Institut für Politische Wissenschaft (Universität München) (Box-folder 94: 15)
  - Gesellschaft zur Förderung des Institutes für Statistik der Minderheitsvölker an der Universität zu Wien (Box-folder 94: 16)
  - Gnosticism (Box-folder 94: 17)
  - Goldmann, Emil (Box-folder 94: 18)
  - Guggenheim Foundation (Box-folder 94: 19)
  - Guyana - Jim Jones cult (Box-folder 95: 1)
  - Haber, Francis C. (Box-folder 95: 2)
  - Hans Kelsen-Institut (Box-folder 95: 3)
  - Hanns-Seidel-Stiftung. See CORRESPONDENCE, Hermann Warth
  - Hatton, Augustus R. (Box-folder 95: 4)
  - Hegel, G. W. F. (Box-folder 95: 5)
  - Heidegger, Martin (Box-folder 95: 6)
  - Hilgenfeld, A. (Box-folder 95: 7)
  - History (Box-folder 95: 8)
  - Hochschule für Politische Wissenschaften, Munich. Includes notes of Eric Voegelin (Box-folder 95: 9)
  - Hochschulverband (Verbandsgruppe Universität München) (Box-folder 95: 10)
  - Imprimis (Center for Constructive Alternatives) (Box-folder 96: 1)
  - Institute for Cross-Cultural and Social-Scientific Research (Box-folder 96: 2-3)
  - Institute for Symbolism. See Institute for Cross-Cultural and Social-Scientific Research
  - Instituto de Estudios Politicos, Madrid (Box-folder 96: 4)
  - International Association for Philosophy of Law and Social Philosophy (Box-folder 96: 5)
  - International Political Science Association. Rome Congress, 1955 (Box-folder 96: 6)
  - International Seminar for Diplomats, Castle of Klessheim near Salzburg (Box-folder 96: 7)
  - James, Henry (Box-folder 96: 8)
  - KAI - Mitteilungen des Lehrstuhls für Soziologie und Kulturwissenschaft an der Universität Salzburg (Box-folder 96: 9)
  - Kant, Immanuel (Box-folder 96: 10)
  - Kelsen, Hans. See Hans Kelsen-Institut
  - Kobell, Ferdinand (Box-folder 97: 1)
  - Konrad-Adenauer-Stiftung. See CORRESPONDENCE, Hermann Warth
  - Law (Box-folder 97: 2)
  - Lenhoff, Arthur (Box-folder 97: 3)
  - Louisiana State University (Box-folder 97: 4)
  - Ludwig Keimer Foundation (Box-folder 97: 5)
  - Luther, Martin (Box-folder 97: 6)
  - Machiavelli, Niccolò (Box-folder 97: 7)
  - Maps (Box-folder 97: 8)
  - Martyrology (Box-folder 97: 9)
  - Marxism (Box-folder 97: 10)
  - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 97: 11)
  - Mises, Ludwig von (Box-folder 97: 12)
    Includes correspondence with Stephan Böhm
  - Musil, Robert. See CORRESPONDENCE, Internationale Robert-Musil Gesellschaft
  - National socialism (Box-folder 97: 13)
  - Nationalism (Box-folder 97: 14)
  - Near East, Ancient (Box-folder 97: 15)
  - Nemo, Saint (Box-folder 97: 16)
  - New School for Social Research (Box-folder 97: 17)
  - North Atlantic Treaty Organization (Box-folder 97: 18)
  - Nova, Fritz (Box-folder 97: 19)
  - O'Connor, Flannery (Box-folder 97: 20)
  - O'Connor, R. Eric (Box-folder 97: 21)
  - Opus Dei (Spain) (Box-folder 97: 22)
  - Pansophie (Box-folder 97: 23)
  - Paranoia and pronoia (Box-folder 97: 24)
  - Parliamentary Group for World Government (Box-folder 97: 25)
  - Parmenides (Box-folder 97: 26)